Finding aid to the Beulah Strong Papers CA.MS.00334
Smith College Archives
Beulah Strong Papers
1888-1938
Smith College Archives
Strong, Beulah, 1866-1951
CA.MS.00334
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Professor of Art. Contains biographical information, correspondence, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Beulah Strong was born in 1866. She studied art at the Academies Julian and Colarossi, Paris, in 1887-1891. From 1892-1901, she was an art teacher at Potter College in Bowling Green, KY, and then at Belmont College, Nashville, TN in 1902-1905. From 1907-1923, Strong was an Art Instructor and Associate Professor of Art at Smith College. In 1907-1909, she illustrated Aunt Jane of Kentucky and Land of Long Ago by Eliza Calvert Hall. She retired in 1923 and lived in Italy until WWII. She died in San Francisco, CA, in 1951.
Scope and Contents
The Beulah Strong papers consist primarily of family correspondence, mainly from Beulah Strong's mother, Delia Morris Strong. There is a small amount of biographical information included in the collection, as well as travel photographs of Italy.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Beulah Strong papers were donated to the Smith College Archives from a number of sources.
Strong, Beulah, 1866-1951
- Biography, 1906 (Box 1029, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (from)
  - Beaux, Cecilia, undated (Box 1029, Folder 2)
  - Brandegee, Robert, undated (Box 1029, Folder 3)
  - Elliott, Elizabeth, Feb. 9, 1915 (Box 1029, Folder 4)
  - Folinsbee, John Fulton, May 17, 1916 (Box 1029, Folder 5)
  - Hawthorne, Charles Webster, undated (Box 1029, Folder 6)
  - Manship, Paul, June 23, 1915 (Box 1029, Folder 7)
  - Washington, Booker T. (copy), Nov. 28, 1913 (Box 1029, Folder 8)
- Correspondence (to)
  - Morris, Helen (cousin), Nov. 7, 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 9)
  - Morris, Mary C. (aunt), Jan.-Dec. 1888 (Box 1029, Folder 10)
  - Morris, Mary C. (aunt), Jan.-Nov. 1889 (Box 1029, Folder 11)
  - Morris, Mary C. (aunt), Jan.-Dec. 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 12)
  - Strong, Delia (mother), Sept. 1888 (Box 1029, Folder 13)
  - Strong, Delia (mother), Sept. 1889 (Box 1029, Folder 14)
  - Strong, Delia (mother), Dec. 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 15)
  - Strong, Delia (mother), 1891 (Box 1029, Folder 16)
  - From Beulah and Delia Strong to Morris, Mary C., 1890-1891 (Box 1029, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous correspondence
  - Billings, Julia M. to Morris, Mary C., 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 18)
  - Kellogg, Alice to Billings, Julia M., June 19, 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 19)
  - Morris, Helen to Morris, Mary C., Jan. 16, 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 20)
  - Strong, Delia to Morris, Mary C., Jan.-Dec. 1888 (Box 1029, Folder 21)
  - Strong, Delia to Morris, Mary C., 1889 (Box 1029, Folder 22)
  - Strong, Delia to Morris, Mary C., Jan.-Dec. 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 23)
  - Strong, Delia to Morris, Mary C., Jan.-June; 1891 (Box 1029, Folder 24)
  - Strong, Ned to Strong, Delia, 1890 (Box 1029, Folder 25)
  - Wheeler, Mannie C. to Strong, Delia, undated (Box 1029, Folder 26)
- Photographs, 1938; undated (Box 1029, Folder 27)